13290 Mohican Ct. Carmel, IN 46033 cell: (317) 289-7294

Summary

Successfully applied knowledge and skills in budget management, innovative resource utilization and project organization to deliver IT solutions. Experienced the span of the IT lifecycle having served as an operator, programmer, manager, project manager and IT executive with a strong record of providing project management that meets stakeholders requirements. All of these positions have helped develop my skills and ability to lead projects with strong, confident and technically capable teams. My experience in the projects below has a consistent thread and that is a strong, capable team, knowledgeable in the area of the project requirements led by a competent, dedicated manager that successfully completes projects on time and on budget.

Experience

FULLBEAUTY BRANDS, Indianapolis, Indiana

Vice-President IT Technical Services and Operations, March 2002 – May 2017

Management of IT Technical Services and Operations teams in the procurement, installation, maintenance and operation of infrastructure necessary for providing an environment for the business units to excel in their areas. Responsible as well for recruiting, developing and managing of the technical teams comprising Operations, Network, Client/Server, Database and Systems Architects that in addition to their normal operational duties, served with me on the many infrastructural projects described below. I had responsibility of IT budgeting and cost control working very closely with Finance to keep IT spend at or below 2% of annual sales.

Ticketing and Problem/Change Conversion (Jul 2016 – May 2017)

Replaced various single purpose ticketing and problem/change management executing on multiple platforms and no uniformity with Jira/Confluence software providing improved and consistent desktop/smartphone ticketing, problem/change management, and IT data archival.

- All ticketing applications used by IT to fulfill user requirements were identified and
 converted utilizing built-in capabilities of the Jira/Confluence environment. This provided
 an easier to use and more consistent interface for users, resulting in increased productivity
 and improved IT metrics.
- IT was able to create a new integrated ticketing system for use by Human Resources to assist in onboarding of new associates as well as a redeveloped ticketing system for other user departments requiring IT assistance with desktops, laptops and mobile devices.

El Paso Call Center Telemarketing Conversion (Aug 2014 – Dec 2015)

Creation of a robust web-based mid-tier development, testing and production server based system utilizing existing El Paso VMware and Wyse Thin Clients for processing customer orders and customer service for all FBB Brands.

- Technical Services, Applications Development, and El Paso Call Center users met twice weekly to coordinate current sprint goals, testing and UAT requirements and release/deploy/backout (if needed) scheduled for that week.
- Release/deploy/backout (if needed) scheduled for between 1:00 and 7:00 AM MST to minimize impact to El Paso (closed during those hours).
- Results update communicated to all interested parties.

New York IT Infrastructure Move to 1 NY Plaza (Jul 2013 – Jul 2014)

Assigned as IT Infrastructure PM working with a team of 10 Client/Server and Network associates in relocating IT operations and user environment from Times Square to South Manhattan. All of FULLBEAUTY Brands was moving to new location and I had responsibility

13290 Mohican Ct. Carmel, IN 46033

cell: (317) 289-7294

for IT Infrastructure servers, network, software, desktops and printers. Also, established Wi-Fi throughout new office areas at 1 NY Plaza.

- Agreements with NY stakeholders resulted in project plan to move office staff over 2 weekends with communications established between new and old sites.
- All network requirements for users to communicate from either the old or new site were made operational before 1st week user moves. The 2nd week user moves were executed without incident or negative impact. Application servers were moved to the new site after 2nd week user moves.
- Entire project executed on time and on budget.

Lotus Notes Conversion to MS Outlook Web Access (May 2011 – Feb 2012)

Conversion of old Lotus Notes environment to current MS cloud based OWA system that would support newer iPhone and Android technology as well as provide a basis for MS Office365 environment migration.

- Established OWA cloud requirements, policies, distribution lists, meetings, calendar data, shared mailboxes and batch email jobstreams.
- Training for the new system was provided to the users prior to migration.
- Enable future plans to migrate to desktop copies of MS Office to Office365 that would simplify Office release currency, platform independence (Windows, Mac, iPad, etc.)

PCI/DSS Compliance (Apr 2006 – Nov 2007)

Responsible for overall coordination, senior management involvement, funding and support, departmental cooperation and liaison with internal audit team and PCI/DSS QSA.

- Worked with IT Applications Development to reduce number of credit card files to one and created a development API to request credit card number based on a token. This greatly reduced the complexity involved with:
 - o Credit card numbers in transit and at rest
 - o Right to access compliance for IT and users
 - o Simplified required annual credit card number reencryption
- Logging of all access to Network, Servers and Applications within Credit Card environment.
- Monthly, Quarterly scans of Network and Server accessibility to monitor access and identify needed Network and Operating System patches.

Director, Computer Operations and Technical Support, February 1998 – March 2002 Responsibility for IT Operations, IT Network, IT Client/Server and IT Budgeting in addition to the IT Technical Support (mainframe) group.

Convert Mainframe Financials to Oracle EBS (2001 – 2003)

Led IT Technical Services teams in working with IT Applications and Systems Integration Partner resources in conversion of mainframe based McCormick & Dodge financials system to Oracle EBS R11i (Enterprise Business System) executing on a mid-tier server complex.

- Oracle Financials EBS featured web-based interface increasing user productivity, less training time for company financial reporting, procurement and asset tracking.
- Data previously manually entered into the McCormick & Dodge system was converted into batch file feeds to the Oracle EBS database.

Senior Manager, Technical Support, May 1992 – February 1998 **Manager, Technical Support,** May 1989 – May 1992 13290 Mohican Ct. Carmel, IN 46033

cell: (317) 289-7294

Responsibility for IT Technical Support group and all hardware/software activity and control for IBM mainframe environment.

Senior Software Specialist, April 1984 – May 1989

Systems lead for MVS, JES2, SMP/E, VSAM, CICS, JCL, and Batch. Developed various tools for operational and costs saving improvements such as:

- Batch CICS communications facility that could issue CEMT commands such as open/close online datasets for batch processing.
- Converted CA-Librarian source maintenance to in-house system to facilitate source control with backup and archival capabilities.

CNA INSURANCE, Chicago, Illinois

CICS and IMS Manager, July 1983 – April 1984

Responsible for leading the CICS and IMS teams supporting CNA IT development efforts.

PT COMPONENTS, Indianapolis, Indiana

Software Specialist, September 1982 – July 1983

Responsible for leading software team in supporting new company created from FMC. Also had major role in creation of new data center with appropriate hardware and software for new company.

EDUCATION

Ball State University Accounting, History

CERTIFICATIONS

Project Management Professional (PMP) Active - Project Management Institute

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Mac OS, MS Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint), Visio, JIRA/Confluence